<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>frikyfriky11</title><link>https://frikyfriky11.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on frikyfriky11</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 22:55:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frikyfriky11.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup passwordless access via SSH to a remote server</title><link>https://frikyfriky11.github.io/posts/passwordless-access-ssh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 22:55:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://frikyfriky11.github.io/posts/passwordless-access-ssh/</guid><description>Managing remote servers is part of my job as a software engineer, and I usually access them via SSH.
One thing that is really annoying is typing your password every single time, and for obvious reason setting an empty password is not a workaround :)
SSH servers usually support key authentication besides password authentication (sometimes it is even the only method of authentication allowed!), and making the server trust your computer is trivially easy to do.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://frikyfriky11.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 21:43:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://frikyfriky11.github.io/about/</guid><description>Since I was four years old I have been immersed in the world of information technology.
I started my journey by installing my favorite games and destroying several operating systems (sorry Windows 98, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t your fault!), then I moved on to discover the world of the web, HTML (at the time it wasn&amp;rsquo;t HTML5 yet) and a pinch of JavaScript.
My curiosity then extended to the world of hardware but also virtual machines, creating entire distributed networks in VMs on the home PC and fiddling a little too much with the router.</description></item><item><title>Batch rotating multiple mp4 videos (useful for Instagram Reels)</title><link>https://frikyfriky11.github.io/posts/batch-rotating-mp4-videos-for-reels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 21:43:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://frikyfriky11.github.io/posts/batch-rotating-mp4-videos-for-reels/</guid><description>Whenever I have some free time (almost never these days, sigh!), you can find me shooting photos around the city. Usually I like to post the best content of a shooting day on Instagram, and while I am mostly focused on photography, I sometimes like to post some videos as Instagram Reels as well.
Instagram Reels have a 9:16 aspect ratio (1080x1920) while my camera (a Canon EOS R) shoots in 9:16 (1920x1080) and doesn&amp;rsquo;t automatically rotate the videos when I shoot them portrait, unlike the photo mode that does this by default.</description></item></channel></rss>